<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://majulahsingapuri.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Bhargav Singapuri Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://majulahsingapuri.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Bhargav Singapuri Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://majulahsingapuri.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>Bhargav Singapuri</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
        <id>https://majulahsingapuri.github.io/blog/hello-world</id>
        <link href="https://majulahsingapuri.github.io/blog/hello-world"/>
        <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first foray into creating a site.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello one and all!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2><p>I am Bhargav Singapuri, a fresh graduate from NTU and this blog is my attempt to document all my learnings so that I can share them with everyone.
The main aim of this site is for me to share a bit about myself as well as for me to document the work that I do so that you can join me on my journey as a Data Scientist / Software Engineer as I tackle problems at work or in my own personal projects.
By doing this, I hope that we can learn interesting things together and that I can easily recall what I did previously should I need to.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background" title="Direct link to Background">​</a></h2><p>I started my Coding journey back in Secondary school and from the first day knew that I wanted to become someone that codes for a living.
Although I didn't have a clue as to what that would entail, the thought of giving instructions to a computer and have it solve problems was thrilling.</p><p>I started off my journey by participating in the <a href="https://noisg.comp.nus.edu.sg/noi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Olympiad of Informatics</a> and was immediately thron into the deep end of algorithms.
Although I did not understand much of what was going on, being able to at least solve some of the easier questions piqued my interest in the area and drove me to pursue the field further.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="college">College<a href="#college" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to College" title="Direct link to College">​</a></h2><p>In University I studied <a href="https://www.ntu.edu.sg/education/undergraduate-programme/bachelor-of-science-in-data-science-artificial-intelligence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Science and Artificial Intelligence</a> at NTU Singapore.
This was a slight deviation from my pure computer science inclination as I saw the growing importance of data in the current day and really wanted something that would combine my interests in math and coding.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="competitions">Competitions<a href="#competitions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Competitions" title="Direct link to Competitions">​</a></h3><p>Unfortunately due to COVID, a lot of my school experience was cut short and I was unable to join many school related activities that might have bolstered my learning such as hackathons and school clubs.
Despite that, I did manage to join a handful such as <a href="https://hacknroll.nushackers.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NUS Hacknroll</a> and <a href="https://readytradergo.optiver.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Optiver's Ready Trader Go</a>.
Most of these were for the experience and to have some fun with friends rather than to actually win the competition but they were good experiences nonetheless.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="key-subjects">Key Subjects<a href="#key-subjects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Key Subjects" title="Direct link to Key Subjects">​</a></h3><p>Some of the topics that I learned at University are:</p><ol><li>Databases</li><li>Algorithms</li><li>Deep Learning</li><li>Software Engineering</li><li>Information Retrieval</li><li>Machine Learning</li><li>Time Series Analysis</li><li>Multivariate Analysis</li><li>Probability and Statistics</li><li>Calculus</li><li>Linear Programming</li><li>Simulation in Finance</li></ol><p>All of these topics helped build my foundational knowledge in computing as well as mathematics.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="internship">Internship<a href="#internship" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Internship" title="Direct link to Internship">​</a></h3><p>During my time at school, I interned at <a href="https://upskills.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Upskills Pte. Ltd</a> for 3 months, as well as <a href="https://vertexholdings.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vertex Holdings Pte. Ltd</a> for 15 months.
The latter being a part of <a href="https://www.skillsfuture.gov.sg/workstudy/wsdeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Work Study Degree Programme</a> where I had to do an extensive internship and a Final Year Project with the company.</p><p>You can read more details on my experiences in the <code>Projects</code> Section.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="work">Work<a href="#work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Work" title="Direct link to Work">​</a></h2><p>Now that I have completed University, I will be working at UOB Group's Technology Department as a Software Engineer.
I look forward to solving interesting challenges that the bank faces and helping them to build up their infrastructure.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bhargav Singapuri</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/majulahsingapuri</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
    </entry>
</feed>